https://boothwelsh.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy PolicyWebsite Privacy Policy – Third Party Cookies with Analytics
1.0 Background
Booth Welsh Automation Ltd understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used and shared online. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits this website, boothwelsh.co.uk (“Our Site”) and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a manner that is consistent with our obligations and your rights under the law.
Any personal data we do collect will only be used as permitted by law.
All Cookies used by and on Our Site are used in accordance with current Cookie guidance.
1.1 Recital 32
Consent should be given by a clear affirmative act establishing a freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject’s agreement to the processing of personal data relating to him or her, such as by a written statement, including by electronic means, or an oral statement. This could include ticking a box when visiting an internet website, choosing technical settings for information society services or another statement or conduct which clearly indicates in this context the data subject’s acceptance of the proposed processing of his or her personal data. Silence, pre-ticked boxes or inactivity should not therefore constitute consent. Consent should cover all processing activities carried out for the same purpose or purposes. When the processing has multiple purposes, consent should be given for all of them. If the data subject’s consent is to be given following a request by electronic means, the request must be clear, concise and not unnecessarily disruptive to the use of the service for which it is provided.
Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it.
2.0 Definitions and Interpretation
In this Policy, the following terms shall have the following meanings:
Term
Definition
Account
means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Our Site
Cookie
A small text file placed on your computer or device by Our Site when you visit certain parts of Our Site and/or when you use certain features of Our Site.
Cookie Law
Details of the Cookies used by Our Site are set out in Section 15, below; means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003
Personal Data
Any and all data that relates to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified from that data. In this case, it means personal data that you give to Us via Our Site. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the Data Protection Act 2018, OR EU Regulation 2016/679 – the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)
We/Us/Our
Booth Welsh Automation Ltd, a limited company registered in England and Wales under company number 02374159, whose address is 3 Riverside Way, Irvine, KA11 5DJ.
2.0 Information about Us
2.1 Website
Our Site is [owned and] operated by Booth Welsh Automation Ltd, a limited company registered in England and Wales under company number 02374159, whose address is 3 Riverside Way, Irvine, KA11 5DJ.
2.2 VAT information
Our VAT number is GB498 942 179.
2.3 Data Protection Officer
Our Data Protection Officer is Gavin Florence, and can be contacted by;
Email dataprotection@boothwelsh.co.uk
Telephone +44(0)0345 0344344
Post 3 Riverside Way, Irvine, KA11 5DJ.
3.0 What Does This Policy Cover?
This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of Our Site. Our Site may contain links to other websites.
Please note that We have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.
4.0 Your Rights
As a data subject, you have the following rights under the GDPR, which this policy and Our use of personal data have been designed to uphold:
The right to be informed about Our collection and use of personal data;
The right of access to the personal data We hold about you;
The right to rectification if any personal data we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete
The right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask us to delete any personal data We hold about you (We only hold your personal data for a limited time, as explained later in this notice but if you would like us to delete it sooner, please contact us;
The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;
The right to data portability (obtaining a copy of your personal data to re-use with another service or organisation);
The right to object to Us using your personal data for particular purposes; and
Rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.
If you have any cause for complaint about Our use of your personal data, please contact us using the details provided and We will do Our best to solve the problem for you. If We are unable to help, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK’s supervisory authority, the Information Commissioner’s Office.
For further information about your rights, please contact the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.
5.0 What Data Do We Collect?
Depending upon your use of Our Site, We may collect some or all of the following personal [and non-personal] data:
Full name
Business/company name
Job title
Contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers
Demographic information such as post code
IP address
Web browser type and version
Operating system
a list of urls starting with a referring site, your activity on Our Site, and the site you exit to
6.0 How Do We Use Your Data?
All personal data is processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. We will comply with Our obligations and safeguard your rights under the Data Protection Act 2018, and/or GDPR at all times.
Our use of your personal data will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for Our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to Our use of your personal data (e.g. by subscribing to emails), or because it is in Our legitimate interests.
Specifically, We may use your data for the following purposes:
Providing and managing your Account (Booth Welsh Automation Ltd access)
Providing and managing your access to Our Site
Personalising and tailoring your experience on Our Site
Replying to emails from you
Supplying you with emails that you have opted into (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time by using the link included with email
Market research
Analysing your use of Our Site [and gathering feedback] to enable Us to continually improve Our Site [and your user experience]
Where you have selected we may contact you with information, news, and offers on our products and services using the following method(s) which you have chosen:
Email
Telephone
Text message
Post
We will not, however, send you any unsolicited marketing or spam and will take all reasonable steps to ensure that We fully protect your rights and comply with Our obligations under the Data Protection Act 2018, and/or GDPR, and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.
You have the right to withdraw your consent to Us using your personal data at any time, and to request that We delete it. We do not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected.
Data will therefore be retained for the following periods (or its retention will be determined on the following bases):
Website logs will not be retained for more than 32 days
Personal information on the website not relating to User accounts and Media within the website shall not be retained for more than 32 days
User Account information will be removed within 7 days of access no longer being required
7.0 How and Where Do We Store Your Data?
We only keep your personal data for as long as We need to in order to use it as described above, and/or for as long as We have your permission to keep it.
Your data will only be stored within the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein).
You are deemed to accept and agree to this by using Our Site and submitting information to Us. If We do store data outside the EEA, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the Data Protection Act 2018 and/or GDPR including:
Any files transmitted shall be encrypted
All data will be handled in line with relevant agreements.
Data security is very important to Us, and to protect your data We have taken suitable measures to safeguard and secure data collected through Our Site.
Steps We take to secure and protect your data include:
Data not required for the running of the website is removed after 32 days.
Data held on Booth Welsh Servers is only accessible by employees with the appropriate credentials
8.0 Do We Share Your Data?
Subject to the section below, We will not share any of your data with any other third parties for any purposes.
In certain circumstances, We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal data, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with legal obligations, a court order, or a governmental authority.
We may share your data with other companies in the Clough group for where it is deemed relevant to your enquiry. This includes Our holding company and its subsidiaries.
We may sometimes contract with third parties to supply products and services to you on Our behalf. These may include payment processing, delivery of goods, search engine facilities, advertising, and marketing. In some cases, the third parties may require access to some or all of your data. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, Our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under the law.
We may compile statistics about the use of Our Site including data on traffic, usage patterns, user numbers, sales, and other information. All such data will be anonymised and will not include any personally identifying data, or any anonymised data that can be combined with other data and used to identify you.
We may from time to time share such data with third parties such as prospective investors, affiliates, partners, and advertisers. Data will only be shared and used within the bounds of the law.
The third party data processors used by Us and listed below are located. Where We transfer any personal data outside the EEA, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the Data Protection Act 2018, and/or GDPR.
Third Party Site p.typekit.net
Used By Website
Description Tracking image for the font developer
Third Party Business Adobe
Third Party Site maps.googleapis.com
Used By Website
Description Authentication/Fonts/Mapping
Third Party Business Google
Third Party Business Google
In certain circumstances, We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal data, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with legal requirements, a court order, or a governmental authority.
9.0 What Happens If Our Business Changes Hands?
We may, from time to time, expand or reduce Our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Our business. Any personal data that you have provided will, where it is relevant to any part of Our business that is being transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Privacy Policy, be permitted to use that data only for the same purposes for which it was originally collected by Us.
In the event that any of your data is to be transferred in such a manner, you will be contacted in advance and informed of the changes. When contacted you will be given the choice to have your data deleted, or withheld from the new owner or controller.
10.0 How Can You Control Your Data?
In addition to your rights under the GDPR, when you submit personal data via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict Our use of your data. In particular, We aim to give you strong controls on Our use of your data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from Us which you may do by un-subscribing using the links provided in Our emails and at the point of providing your details).
You may also wish to sign up to one or more of the preference services operating in the UK:
The Telephone Preference Service (“the TPS”)
The Corporate Telephone Preference Service (“the CTPS”)
The Mailing Preference Service (“the MPS”).
You can opt out by of many third party cookies by using:
https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/opt-out-cookies.html
http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices
These may help to prevent you receiving unsolicited marketing. Please note, however, that these services will not prevent you from receiving marketing communications that you have consented to receiving.
10.1 Your Right to Withhold Information
You may access [certain areas of] Our Site without providing any data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on Our Site you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.
You may restrict Our use of Cookies. For more information, see Our Cookie Policy Section 11.
10.2 How Can You Access Your Data?
You have the right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). Under the Data Protection Act 2018, and the GDPR, no fee is payable and We will provide any and all information in response to your request free of charge.
Please contact Us for more details at dataprotection@boothwelsh.co.uk, or using the contact details below in Section 12.
11.0 Our Use of Cookies
Our Site may place and access certain first party Cookies on your computer or device. First party Cookies are those placed directly by Us and are used only by Us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve Our products AND/OR services. We have carefully chosen these Cookies and have taken steps to ensure that your privacy and personal data is protected and respected at all times.
By using Our Site, you may also receive certain third party Cookies on your computer or device. Third party Cookies are those placed by websites, services, and/or parties other than Us. Third Party Cookies are used on Our Site for ensuring the visitor get the best user experience and allows us to understand how our site is used. For more details, please refer to Section 6. These Cookies are not integral to the functioning of Our Site and your use and experience of Our Site will not be impaired by refusing consent to them.
All Cookies used by and on Our Site are used in accordance with current Cookie Law.
Before Cookies are placed on your computer or device, you will be shown a prompt/pop-up requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling Us to provide the best possible experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of Our Site may not function fully or as intended.
Certain features of Our Site depend on Cookies to function. Cookie Law deems these Cookies to be “strictly necessary”. These Cookies are shown below. Your consent will not be sought to place these Cookies, but it is still important that you are aware of them. You may still block these Cookies by changing your internet browser’s settings as detailed below, but please be aware that Our Site may not work properly if you do so.
We have taken great care to ensure that your privacy is not at risk by allowing them.
The following Cookies may be placed on your computer or device which may also be used by Analytics:
Cookie Name
Used By
Party
(F / T)
Type
Purpose
Retention/Expiry
1P_JAR
.google.co.uk/.com
T
Advertising
These cookies are used to gather website statistics, and track conversion rates.
1 Month
APISID
.google.co.uk/.com
T
Advertising – Analytics and Personalisation
These cookies from YouTube – allow us to monitor video usage on the website and allow Google to monitor performance of videos preferences and usage as well as to serve personalised advertising Analytics
2 Years
CONSENT
.google.co.uk/.com
T
Advertising – Analytics and Personalisation
Cookie consent setting
20 Years
DV
Personalisation
The NID cookie contains a unique ID Google uses to remember your preferences and other information, such as your preferred language (e.g. English), how many search results you wish to have shown per page (e.g. 10 or 20), and whether or not you wish to have Google’s SafeSearch filter turned on.
6 months
OTZ
www.google.com
T
Used by Google Analytics that provides an aggregate analysis of Website visitors
4 days
SAPISID
.google.co.uk/.com
T
Personalisation
This suite of cookies are used by Google to keep a track of user conversions store preferences and use those preferences to serve (or not serve) advertising around the web based on user interests and engagement.
2 Years
SID
.google.co.uk/.com
T
Analytics
2 Years
SIDCC
.google.com
Advertising – Analytics and Personalisation
Security cookie to protect a user’s data from unauthorized access
2 Years
__cfduid
.browser-update.org
T
Personalisation
Cloud Flare
1 year 6 months
__cfduid
Analytics
Like _ga, this lets us know if you’ve visited before, so we can count how many of our visitors are new to our site or to a certain page
2 Years
__utmb
.jquery.com
T
Analytics
This works with _utmc to calculate the average length of time you spend on our site
30 Mins
__utmc
.jquery.com
T
Analytics
This works with _utmb to calculate when you close your browser
session
__utmt
.jquery.com
T
Analytics
Used to throttle request rate. Expires in 10 min
session
__utmz
.jquery.com
T
Analytics
This tells us how you reached our site (for example from another website or a search engine)
6 months
_ga
.boothwelsh.co.uk
F
Analytics
This helps us count how many people visit our site by tracking if you’ve visited before
2 Years
_gat
.boothwelsh.co.uk
F
Analytics
Used to manage the rate at which page view requests are made
10 Mins
_gid
.boothwelsh.co.uk
F
Analytics
This helps us count how many people visit our site by tracking if you’ve visited before
1 day
In addition to the controls that We provide, you can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. Most internet browsers also enable you to choose whether you wish to disable all Cookies or only third party Cookies. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser or the documentation that came with your device.
You can choose to delete Cookies on your computer or device at any time, however you may lose any information that enables you to access Our Site more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, login and personalisation settings.
It is recommended that you keep your internet browser and operating system up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser and manufacturer of your computer or device if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.
Our Site may place and access certain first party Cookies on your computer or device. First party Cookies are those placed directly by Us and are used only by Us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve Our [products] AND/OR [services].
By using Our Site you may also receive certain third party Cookies on your computer or device. Third party Cookies are those placed by websites, services, and/or parties other than Us. Third party Cookies are used on Our Site for e.g. advertising services. In addition, Our Site uses analytics services as identified in the table above, which also use Cookies. Website analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse usage statistics, enabling Us to better understand how people use Our Site. For more details, please refer to Our Cookie Policy Section 11.
12.0 Contacting Us
If you have any questions about Our Site or this Privacy Policy, please contact Us by email at dataprotection@boothwelsh.co.uk, by telephone on +44(0)345 0344 344, or by post at 3 Riverside Way, Irvine, KA11 5DJ.
Please ensure that your query is clear, particularly if it is a request for information about the data We hold about you.
13.0 Changes to Our Privacy Policy
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time (for example, if the law changes). Any changes will be immediately posted on Our Site and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Our Site following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date.
Last updated 2020-05-17
